Sebastian Heron

sebheron21@hotmail.co.uk | 07392 070399 | github.com/swegrock | linkedin.com/in/sebheron21 | swegrock.github.io

Summary

Creative and versatile Computer Science student, constantly developing intuitive solutions to problems noticed and overlooked. Experience primarily in .NET with C#, but also have experience in VB.NET, VBA, Java, Python and the Web Dev Stack. Knowledge of GIT, TFS and the various database management systems and creation tools incl. Access. Adept understanding of Scrum, Agile, Waterfall and Rapid development methodologies. An enthusiastic innovator and communicator who exceeds expectations. Works effectively as within a team and independently.

Education

Currently in 2nd Year for Bsc (Hons) in Computer Science, Keele University

Studying a wide range of different topics, from AI to Databases, excelling in programming related modules. Currently working at a 1st. My 2nd year module grades are:

Database Systems - 75% (First) Web Technology - 87% (First) Software Engineering - 81% (First)

Advanced Programming - 96% (First) Programming II - 92% (First) Digital Forensics - 66% (2:1)

Computational and Artificial Mobile Application Development -

Intelligence I - 95% (First) 84% (First)

2019 - Present

Level 4 Knowledge Modules, TDM (The Development Manager)

Completed: BCS Software Development Methodologies (QAN: 603/0543/5), Microsoft Technical Associate 98-361 Software Development Fundamentals, Microsoft Technical Associate 98-375: HTML5 Application Developer Fundamentals

2017

Experience

Apprentice Software Engineer, Malvern Panalytical

Code reviewed and performed paired programming tasks to help improve development techniques, code quality, test coverage and efficiency. Worked closely with other Software Engineers, Testers, Other Engineers and Application Scientists. Designed front-end and implemented back-end for highly requested Software features. Worked on modular API packages used for front-end user controls and back-end data structures and implementation.

Sep 2017 – Dec 2018 Enigma Business Park, WR14 1XZ

Work and Volunteering

Sales Assistant, Waitrose

Worked in a tight nit team to complete tasks set by upper management. Tasks included: tidying shop floor, stocking shelves, working on tills, providing customer support. Waitrose prioritises customer service ahead of everything else, facilitating development in my communication and troubleshooting skills.

Aug 2014 – Mar 2017 Edith Walk WR14 4WR

Volunteer, YMCA Worcester

While completing NCS I was given the opportunity to volunteer at the YMCA, tasks included morale boosting and hosting a handful of quiz nights. We also raised money for the charity itself (and another charity Headway) through various mediums including a "hand-car-wash" we held nearby.

Aug 2014 – Mar 2017 Beech Bank, WR5 2BD

Projects

OMNISEC - Multi-detector GPC/SEC system - malvernpanalytical.com/en/products/product-range/omnisec

Complex Software system for interfacing with hardware, used for measuring particle size and other related attributes. Utilized the Scrum development methodology with VSTFS, Ranorex and NUnit for testing and other frameworks including Prism, Unity containers and Telerik UI.

Stacket - Kanban style to-do board for increasing development speed - swegrock.github.io/stacket

Widget style Kanban board application used to organize the development of projects on the go. Built from the ground up with custom UI components designed to be minimalist.

JazzNotes - Notes application for jazz transcriptions - swegrock.github.io/jazznotes

Cross platform jazz transcription notes taking application, specifically designed to improve the workflow of a jazz musician. Uses the open-source development package Avalonia to allow building for multiple platforms.

Awards

Top 5%, Credit Suisse

Coding competition limited to university students. Finished 30th out of 950+ participants, beating Oxbridge and UCL students.

2020

References

Natalie Chatley, UK HR Manager, *Malvern Panalytical* natalie.chatley@malvernpanalytical.com

John Palmer, Head of IT, *The Chase School* jpalmer@chase.worcs.sch.uk